Joy Christy Y (1) Featured

Lead Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Java, J2EE, C#, AWS, Cloud, SpringBoot, Eclipse, Docker, HTML, AJAX, JIRA, SQL, Git, Maven, Javascript, Web Services.REST

Current Designation: Lead Software Designer Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Ocean of Awareness Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [HR/Industrial Relations]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: lead software engineer, software developer, application support, project management, quality

management,java,j2ee,c#,aws,cloud,springboot,eclipse,docker,html,ajax,jira,sql,git,maven,javascript, scrum master,

agile, web services, rest, Java 8

Email - id Verified: Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

A Software Professional holding an overall work experience of 14+ years in Java/J2EE/Cloud technologies seeking a suitable position in your esteemed organisation. An aspiring leader, with good people management skills, also holding a PGDBA specializing in Human Resource Management.

Work Experience

Ocean of Awareness as Lead Software Designer

Feb 2019 to Till Date

AWARE - Wellness management solution

Product overview: Being in the space of wellness/health, Aware 1.0 has capabilities to manage the healing life cycle aspects related to a Customer. Being a Customer Centric product, it is a Multi-tenant application that integrates dynamic healing modalities. One of the novel features available is runtime decision making through the support of custom rule engine and AI capabilities, tailored for healing/wellness needs.

Project responsibilities: Defining the overall technical design of the project, POC to identify the usage of Al services such as 'Natural Language Classifier', 'Speech to Text for arriving at Cognitive decisions, Componentizing the software code-base for increased maintainability and to support better evolutionary aspects

Tektronix as Lead Engineer Aug 2008 to Jan 2019

Project overview: Aurora is an automated "next generation" file-based QC product, which integrates into file-based workflows that are processing a large volume of content. The software Reduces the "human QC" efforts, qualifies the media to pass or fail, and aids operational decisions. This product provides both broadcast and production operations with a fast, cost effective QC solution.

Project responsibilities: Designated modules ownership, Licensing Design and Management, Collaborating with the cross site teams, Handling Cloud requirements, Analysis,

Scheduling, Design, Development, Web Services, Bug Fixing, Enhancements and Documentation.

Duration: 3 years

QCloud - World's first Media Content Validation Solution on Cloud - A metered billing solution for Media QC: 3.5 years

Project overview QCloud is a fully automated Cloud QC platform that will ensure the integrity, compliance and quality of media in Cloud workflow. Optimized to be used on Amazon Web Services, QCloud is a highly scalable platform that can operate on a single EC2 instance or can be run on hundreds of EC2 instance to meet workflow scale requirements. QCloud is pre-integrated with most popular 3rd party video servers, automation or asset/media management systems to ensure smooth interoperability. Project responsibilities: Technical Lead for the later releases of the product. Handled the complete ownership of Licensing on Cloud, Implemented the metering solution for the product, Integrated Sentinel Cloud in the product, Incorporated High availability by using Load Balancers in AWS, Web Services development.

Project overview: Hydra is the frame accurate file-based player and is integrated with Aurora (Automated QC product) to provide an efficient manual review workflow.

Project responsibilities: Architecture validation, Design of the Websockets layer for client server communication, Ownership of the complete middle tier, Development, Enhancements and Documentation.

Duration: 8 months

Cerify - Media Content Verification Product - Tektronix

Project overview: This product is used to perform automated media content verification. It takes media files of various formats and applies the different checks against it and reports any violations against the expected standards configured by the customer.

Project responsibilities: Designated modules ownership, Licensing Design and Management, Clustering solution implementation and High Availability in Clustering, Web Services. Mentoring junior team members, Analysis, Scheduling, Design, Development, Bug Fixing, Enhancements and Documentation.

Subex Limited as System Analyst

Mar 2007 to Jul 2008

Project overview: The Concilia - IXBSNG product for British Telecom, had been designed to meet the complex needs that may arise from national Interconnect and ITU Settlement agreements. The system supports the end to end process starting from CDR loading and ending in statement and settlement production. The Concilia has the unique ability to rate a CDR any number of times. It is this key feature that enables it to manage complex correspondent agreements where revenue is shared amongst multiple operators. Project responsibilities: Analysis, Design, Development, Bug Fixing, Enhancements and Documentation. Had also been assigned team coordination and team management tasks.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from panimalar engineering college, chennai in 2004

PG: MBA/PGDM (HR/Industrial Relations) from Symbiosis Centre for Distance Learning (SCDL) in 2010

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Core Java 8, C#, XML, Amazon AWS	
Servlets, JSP, Struts, JDBC, JNDI	
Hibernate, Spring, Spring Boot	
Node js, React js, Javascript	
HTML, AJAX, BEA Weblogic, GIT,	
Eclipse, Intellij Idea, Visual Studio	
JIRA agile, Agilo, OpenProj	
jUnit, SOAP UI, JProfiler	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Tamil				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time